

# **Omer Kamal Ali Ebead**

Nationality: Sudanese Date of birth: 14/06/1998

**Care Phone number:** (+249) 118912916

Email address: <a href="mailto:omerebead1998@gmail.com">omerebead1998@gmail.com</a>

(S) Whatsapp Messenger: 00249118912916

• Home: 11111 Khartoum (Sudan)

### **ABOUT ME**

A motivated and Proactive Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in creating and executing innovative software solutions to enhance business productivity. Highly experienced in software development lifecycle. Also, I have a first class degree in Electrical and electronic engineering from university of Khartoum and I was one of the best 100 student in Sudan in high school Exams. Interested in Computer Science field which I find very helpful in solving today's problems.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software engineer**

AmunData [ 01/11/2022 - 01/08/2023 ]

City: Khartoum Country: Sudan

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/company/amundata

- Full-stack developer using reactis and flask py
- Business intelligence using Power bi
- developing and maintaining Arab organization for agricultural development Platform

### Software developer

**OROOMA** [ 01/05/2022 - 01/11/2022 ]

City: Khartoum
Country: Sudan

Website: https://orooma.com

- Frontend developer using reactis
- Backend developer using nodejs
- Full-stack developer using MERN stack and Kotlin

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

### Software development

Git / REST API management / DBMS: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server / Flutter (basic) / MERN Stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS) / Flutter Basic Skills / kotlin Programming / Python

### **Graphic Design and UI/UX**

Figma & Adobe XD / Adobe: Photoshop, Illsutrator, Lightroom

### **Data Analysis**

Power BI Power Query

### **Machine learning**

Computer Vision / Deep Learning frameworks: PyTorch,Tensorflow,Keras

#### Other Skills

Microsoft Office package: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access / Arduino, Microcontrollers

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Arabic

Other language(s):

**English** French

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### Bachelor degree in electrical and electronic engineering

**University of Khartoum** [ 01/01/2015 - 01/01/2021 ]

City: Khartoum Country: Sudan

Website: https://uofk.academia.edu/

Final grade: 8.14

### **High School Diploma**

Al Mashaail High School [ 01/01/2012 - 01/01/2015 ]

City: Khartoum Country: Sudan Final grade: 93.9

### **CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS**

### Deep learning Indaba.

[ South Africa, 01/10/2018 - 15/10/2018 ]

The Deep Learning Indaba is the annual meeting of the African machine learning and AI community with the mission to Strengthen African AI.

Link: https://deeplearningindaba.com/2023/

### **PROJECTS**

### Arab organization for agricultural development Platform

[ 01/11/2022 - Current ]

Developing a platform for Arab organization for agricultural development.

# Temporal Analysis of Regional Sustainability Using CNNs and Satellite Data

[01/10/2021 - 01/04/2022]

Using computer vision and satellite imagery to classify LULC and also to calculate Biocapacity and test the model in Sudan Satellite images.

#### Suhub Webapp

[ 01/05/2022 - 01/11/2022 ]

Webapp for recruitment developed using Kotlin and Kunafa framework.

#### **Logistics Webapp**

[ 01/05/2022 - 01/11/2022 ]

Webapp to deliver logistics supposed to be published in Saudi Arabia.

Link: https://logistics-dashboard-n39th.ondigitalocean.app/

### **Sun Tracking Car**

[01/06/2018 - 01/08/2018]

- A small car with solar panels on top of it. charge it self and your batteries , after that it rests in a shadow area and turns off.
- Uses Arduino Uno Microcontroller.
- Presented at EEESE 2018.

#### **Conference Gloves**

[01/06/2017 - 01/08/2017]

- A glove integrated with Arduino Uno which control mouse movement/ clicks in your laptop.
- Presented in FFFSF conference 2017

# **VOLUNTEERING**

# **Deep learning IndabaX**

[Sudan, 01/01/2021 - 01/05/2021]

The Deep Learning Indaba is the annual meeting of the Sudanese machine learning and AI community with the mission to Strengthen African AI.

### **Committee of Service and Change.**

[Sudan, 01/11/2019 - 01/11/2021]

Deliver and facilitate services from Sudanese government to Sudanese citizens and help them with their daily life needs.

### **Electrical and Electronics Engineering Students Exhibition (EEESE)**

[Sudan, 01/06/2016 - 01/08/2018]

Electrical and Electronics Engineering Students' Exhibition (EEESE) is an annual event organized by University of Khartoum, Electrical and Electronic Engineering department students.

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/company/eeese/?trk=ppro\_cprof&originalSubdomain=sn

### **Outstanding Students Committee**

[ Sudan, 01/10/2016 - 01/10/2018 ]

Community to help junior outstanding students in Sudan.

Link: https://web.facebook.com/Elmoltga

### **IEEE** student paper contest

[ Sudan, 01/03/2016 - 01/06/2016 ]

#### **COURSES**

#### Al For Everyone

[ 01/09/2019 - 01/11/2019 ]

Link: https://coursera.org/share/7eeb3100b4fa9ebb01a8b4ee992fc94b

#### **Convolutional Neural Networks**

[01/09/2018 - 01/11/2018]

Link: https://coursera.org/share/7f2aa6a0b13c97b4a70df4b42244bbd2

### **Sequence Models**

[01/09/2018 - 01/11/2018]

Link: https://coursera.org/share/b884cebba1b61a72f9b55e46a9b1f275

# **Neural Networks and Deep Learning**

[01/08/2018 - 01/10/2018]

Link: https://coursera.org/share/a4e9dbf92963b8d32c4443d940e466b7

### **REFERENCES**

# **Hiba Hassan Sayed Mohamed Ali**

- Deputy dean of Faculty of engineering, University of Khartoum.
- Hiba\_im@hotmail.com

### **Anas Showk**

- Associate Professor
- Electrical and Electronic Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, University of Khartoum.
- · anas.showk@uofk.ed
- 00249155664062

### **Amal Elsamani Ahmed Taha**

- Lecturer at the University of Khartoum
- University of Oxford, M.Sc., 2022
- Istanbul Technical University, M.Sc., 2017
- amalelsamaniahmedtaha@gmail.com
- amal.elsamani@uofk.edu
- 00249912221881

#### **Omer Hamdi**

- CEO of AMUNDATA.
- omer@amundata.com

#### **Mohamed Satti**

- · CEO of OROOMA.
- m.satti@orooma.com.